This guy turned 420 bucks into almost
half a million dollars on Penguin Coin
this January. Let that sink in. So yes,
insane money is still being made in meme
coins, but let's be real. It's not 2024
anymore. Volume is down. There are
hundreds of bump coins draining
liquidity. Roguers got smarter and 90%
of launches are designed to farm you. So
in this video, I'm breaking down
everything. All my best filters from
previous videos, new red flags I've been
seeing behind the scenes and the exact
checklist you can use before you ape
into a coin. By the end of this video,
you will know exactly how to eliminate
most rugs and garbage coins and focus
only on the ones that have a chance to
print. Let's get into it. All right, so
people always ask me, Vlad, share your
filters. I want to become a millionaire.
Listen, if you slap on too many filters
here in the new pairs, in the final
stretch, and in the migrated tab, you're
going to miss a lot of good coins. Okay,
so there is two types of filters. The
first type is the actual filters. Make
sense. And the second type is your
visual filter, your scanner as I say.
>> [snorts]
>> Now I'll explain what I mean right now.
So, right away we're looking at all
these coins. And from all these coins
you see tweet coins that look something
like that, where the person explains the
narrative of a coin and attaches the
community link. In this case it's not a
community link, in this case it's some
dodgy link, but never mind. Then we've
got community coins with two little blue
gentlemen. In this case we have a cat
saying "Ni hao." Shout out to my Chinese
subscribers. Ni hao cat is your digital
lucky charm on the Solana blockchain. I
am 100% sure that the person that
created this coin is unemployed. And
we've got Twitter profile coins with one
blue [__] Now, about the visual
scanner, about your visual filters. When
you see a Twitter profile coin, you stay
away from it. 90% of Twitter profile
coins are usually AI tech fee
distribution coins or whatever, like for
example this one. Let's see. AMB, answer
matching behavior. Answer matching
behavior. And let me guess,
answer matching behavior. What is the
purpose of the coin? Answer matching
behavior. What is answer matching
behavior? Only the dev knows what is
answer matching behavior, but it doesn't
really matter. I'll tell you why.
Because he rugged the coin. But jokes
aside, coins with this one blue person,
so Twitter profile coins, are much less
likely to pump than tweets and community
coin. Because some traders they don't
even click on these buttons. They just
uh put their cursor on this icon for
example, and they read this.
If you put your cursor on the profile
icon, the only thing you see is answer
matching behavior. Because in meme
coins, speed is everything. We will
return to more scanning techniques at
the end of the video in the before aping
checklist, but for now I'll walk you
through my personal filters in the new
pairs section, in the final stretch, and
in the migrated tab. Let's start with
new pairs. The only protocols you have
to select is pump fun and bonk. Do not
select any other protocols. You will
lose all your money if you select other
protocols. It's very, very risky and you
realistically do not need anything else
apart from pump fun and bonk. Some
people like to filter out top 10
holders, dev holding percentage,
snipers, insiders. I mean, you can do
that. You you'll be on the safe side,
but you might miss very good coins. You
know what I'm saying? So I think the
only filters you actually need, in my
personal opinion, is minimum of $7,000
market cap. That way you'll not see
coins launched by 15-year-olds that are
like, oh yeah, let's launch a coin.
Let's call it
fart coin two and it's going to
go to 1 billion. Yeah, those coins they
have zero chance of pumping and they
have 100% chance of distracting your
attention. And my favorite filter out of
all of them is global fees paid. Once
again, because this video sums
everything up from my old videos along
with some very important new concepts,
I'll quickly explain what global fees
are. So think of them as a piggy bank.
So every time a coin is being traded, a
small percentage of every trade is being
stored in the piggy bank. So
essentially, the more trades, the larger
the piggy bank. Okay, let me just remove
this filter here. I'm going to show you
an example. If we've got coins like
this, the coin is sitting at $61,000
market cap and the global fees paid are
0.6 Solana. And then okay, I'm going to
I'm going to show you another example.
We've got a coin here that's sitting at
just $15,000 market cap. And here the
global fees paid are five Solana. So you
see that there's a bit of a mismatch. So
clearly this coin is not organic. The
whole chart looks extremely artificial.
Those little buys here are 100% bundled.
I can prove it in the transaction
history as well, but I'll explain in
more detail how to analyze the trade
section in a bit. So yeah, for the new
pairs, minimum market cap of 7,000 and
minimum global fees paid 0.3 Solana.
Final stretch. Here pretty much you just
increase the market cap from 7,000 to
8,000. You can keep it at 7,000. It's
not a big of a difference. And the
global fees paid you can increase it
with 0.5 Solana. What you can add here
in the order tab for the final stretch
section is the maximum age of 70
minutes. And yeah, I'm not sure if I
mentioned it, you have to select pump
fun and bonk in all of the sections, in
the new pairs, in the final stretch, and
in the migrated. To save the filters,
you just click apply all. As I
previously told you guys, in meme coins,
speed is everything. A slow trade can
cost you thousands of dollars in your
meme coin journey. So we have to make
our trading layout as easy and as simple
as possible. So I really recommend you
to set up quick buy options in all of
these sections. You can do it simply by
clicking here on the lightning logo. And
then you just adjust this depending on
your trading budget. What I have here
set up is 0.3 for the new pairs, 0.5 for
the final stretch, and one Solana for
the migrated tab. That way I can just
analyze the coin like this, read the
tweet, understand the narrative, check
the global fees, check the volume, check
the market cap, check the most important
token info here, and if I decide to buy
the coin, I just click this button and
it's bought. Really useful feature. By
the way, as you can see, I'm using
Axiom. This is my favorite trading
platform. In my opinion, it's the
fastest and overall most complete. But
if you are using a different trading
platform, that is completely fine. You
are able to set up all these things as
well. It's just going to be a bit
different because the interface is
different and I'm not sure how their
interface works, but rest assured,
everything that we're changing here can
be changed as well on your trading
platform. Now that we have the filters
set up, now that we set up our quick buy
option, you need to understand the
risks. And I'm not saying this because
every YouTuber has to say it. I'm saying
this because trading with the amount of
money you cannot afford to lose will
result in you trading emotionally. And
if you trade emotionally, once you buy
into a coin, you will be extremely
scared to hold it. And if you start
panic selling, you're going to be losing
money on fees all the time. You're going
to have extremely bad exits and trading
is just not going to work out for you.
You need to put your emotions aside. If
you cannot afford to lose this money, do
not trade meme coins. You just need to
understand that before you become
profitable, you are going to lose money
and you need to accept it. Now, I
already told you that I'm using Axiom. I
already told you that Axiom, in my
opinion, is the fastest and the most
convenient platform for trading meme
coins. And right now I'll show you some
of the things Axiom can do. So let's
start with Twitter tracker because in my
opinion, it has one of the best Twitter
trackers, one of the most convenient
Twitter trackers. To set it up, you just
click on trackers and here we've got
Twitter alerts on the right with all the
latest news I have set up. And to add
and remove Twitter accounts for this
Twitter alerts section, you just click
on customize feed, then click add
handle, and add any Twitter account that
you want to track. And then after when
you're scanning meme coins here, you can
click on this X social icon at the
bottom and boom, you have your Twitter
alerts right on your trading screen,
which is really, really convenient. Then
wallet tracking. As you probably noticed
throughout my video, I've been getting
some
Yes, like this, some notifications of
the wallets I'm tracking. Let's track
the guy that made half a million dollars
from 420 bucks, the one I told you about
at the beginning of the video. To do
that, we click on the Penguin Coin,
search for the top traders of the coin,
and let's search for the guy that bought
in with $420 and sold for almost half a
mil. So we've got one here. I think
that's the one I showed you in the
beginning of the video. But we've also
got this one. That's sold for $544,000.
Let's click on it. Let's click on the
wallet activity. And here we see that
the wallet is not really active. In the
past one day he has not been active. In
the past seven days he has not been
active. This wallet is not active. This
wallet is useless to track. So let's
find something else. Okay, I found this
wallet. It looks interesting. It looks
pretty active. And if you want to track
it, you just click on the star icon and
it's done. Now make sure you rename the
wallet. Let's call him penguin and you
can make a custom emoji that will be
visible on charts. So I think in this
case the best emoji is a penguin emoji.
Now you're going to get notifications
from his every trade and you'll be able
to see them on the charts. Also, by
using absolutely anyone's referral link
to set up an account on Axiom, you will
get 10% of all trading fees. It will be
very unwise not to use this advantage
and very conveniently, my referral link
is in the description. So yeah, jokes
aside, I'll be very grateful if you use
my link because I'll get a small
commission from your trades. Let's move
on. The next tip is to have someone to
trade with. It will first of all become
much more fun because meme coins are
supposed to be fun. They're supposed to
be funny. Like look at this.
Fart hub.
Isn't it funny? It's hilarious. So yeah,
if you start acting irrationally, if
you're like, oh yeah, [__] it. I have
nothing to lose. I'm going to buy this
coin, you know? If you start acting like
this, a right group of people will stop
you. The right group of people will
bring you back to reality and it's very
important. And if you don't have any
friends, it's completely fine. I mean,
it's not really fine. I think you should
start socializing a bit more, but I have
a solution for you. I invite you to my
Discord server where you can just chat
to other traders completely for free.
And also, most importantly, hop on live
trading calls with them completely free
of charge. But make sure you join only
after you finish this video. Once again,
I'll quickly walk you through my trading
presets because I always keep getting
messages that people are just losing
money on gas fees, on priority fees.
They have some issues with slippage.
Listen, if you're trading with around
0.2, 0.5, 0.6 Solana, in this range, you
can use my trading presets that are
working great for me. So make sure that
your MEV mode is off if you're trading
with 0.5. If you're trading with
anything less than 0.7 Solana, you don't
even have to put reduced. The chance of
you getting MEVed with that trading
budget is very, very close to zero and
you'll just waste money by having it on
secure. If you're extra paranoid, just
put it to reduced, but I just keep it
off. And these are my sell settings. You
can copy them as well. So let's say you
like this coin, you want to buy it and
you want to buy it at like now at 80K
and you want to sell it at 100K, but you
don't have time to sit here and just
watch the chart and watch it go to 100k
hopefully. Or you're very sleepy and you
want to place a trade and go to sleep
and wake up to a million dollars. I
don't know. In this situation, you can
use limit orders. So, you can buy on
limit and sell on limit. Let's say you
want to buy a dip. A good dip here would
be around 60k. You can press limit,
amount, so let's say 0.5 Solana, and
change the market cap to 60,000 and
press buy. Now, Axiom is going to
automatically buy this coin as soon as
it reaches $60,000 market cap. Oh, [__]
let's cancel let's cancel. That was
close. It would have been very funny if
it crashed to like 20k just for you guys
to see how it works, but never mind. And
now let's say we bought here and we want
to sell at 100. What we do is click on
sell, limit, enter 100,000 here, select
the amount and percentage how much you
want to sell. So, in my case, let's say
it's 100% and then you click sell and
then you can peacefully go to bed and
hope that it grows while you sleep.
Really helpful and very useful. Now,
finally, my 2026 meme coin checklist
before aping. Number one, do you have at
least one or two wallets buying into the
coin? Let's click on this coin as an
example. What do I mean by good traders?
Good traders are either KOLs that you
can see here that are automatically
detected by Axiom. Or if you see that
some of the good wallets that you're
tracking aped into the coin. Do not copy
trade. I repeat it once again. I made a
video about copy trading. It didn't end
well. Tracking wallets and copying
wallets are two different concepts.
Wallet tracking just helps you see where
the traders' attention is and you're
using your own skills and risk analysis
to decide if you want to buy into a coin
or not. I'll show you an example. So,
this coin, as you can see, we have a lot
of KOLs, we have a lot of wallets. So,
this is not a KOL, this is one of the
wallets that I'm tracking. We have a lot
of successful wallets buying into the
coin. Let's say the chart starts here.
If you see a chart like that, that's a
red flag. It doesn't necessarily mean
that the coin is [__] but in my
opinion, it rings a bell. I'll switch
off the global fees filter so that you
can see the [__] coins. Let's start with
this one. So, in this case, everything
about this coin is bad. No KOLs, no
tracked wallets, the graph looks
extremely artificial, really low global
fees. This coin is a total red flag.
It's a total no, zero. There's a zero
chance of this coin doing well, zero.
Now, this is a dangerous one. Well,
first of all, the what gives it off is
this big green candle here. Then once
again, zero KOLs, the coin is at half a
million market cap, and the global fees
are smaller than a coin with
9,000 market cap. And again, you see,
even though the graph here looks pretty
good, there is zero good wallets buying
into the coin. I wonder why. Now, you
see how good the global fees filter is
working. Number two, how many people are
watching the coin and compare that
number to the amount of holders. What do
I mean by that? Okay, let's pick a coin
from the final stretch, the X trader
coin, that's 40 minutes old. The number
of holders of this coin is 160 and the
number of people watching this coin at
the moment is only 25. This means that
there's much more wallets than actual
people. This can mean that it's a
bundle. This can mean that there's a lot
of multi-wallet traders and both of
these things are not really good. So, I
would search for a coins that have
similar number of holders and people
watching the coin. I'll show you an
example. You see, we're all about
examples here on this channel.
Subscribe.
That That was very convincing. That was
extremely convincing. Little duck.
88 watching, 86 holders. Realistic.
Number three, obviously check token
info. I don't think it needs much
explaining to be honest. Everyone is
talking about checking this top 10
holders, dev holder percentage, snipers,
insiders, bundlers, liquidity pool
burned. Except this is pretty
unnecessary because from the filters we
selected, pump fun and bonk, it's
impossible to withdraw liquidity. So, in
all of the coins that you see here, the
liquidity pool is 100% burned, so you're
safe. I would not worry too much about
this because nowadays, in 2026, a lot of
devs use the bundles just for the people
to see the coin. They're not using it to
rug you. They're not using it to rug the
coin. They're just using to artificially
attract buyers, which is not a really
good thing. It's not really ethical, but
there's nothing ethical in meme coins.
One of the green flags in bundles is
that they're decreasing. You see,
they're now at 27%. They're going to
eventually drop to like 10%, 26%. This
is a good bundle. The devs are using
bundles to push the coin up to over 10k
because we have 7k filter here. Some
people have 10 Most people have 10k
filters and just for the traders to see
the coin, the coin needs to pump to over
10k. Some devs definitely use bundles to
rug you. They just buy from different
wallets, from 100 wallets, and just nuke
the chart and leave you broke. And also,
it's obviously better to buy coins after
the dev has sold because some people
tell me, "But Vlad, if the dev keeps
holding the coin, doesn't it mean he
trusts the project?" No, he'll just sell
on you. After he sees a PNL of like 5k,
he'll completely forget about this
project, forget about you, take his
cash, and bounce. And if it's still
early on, the chart might not recover.
If you want a more detailed analysis of
token info, either drop a comment or
text me on Discord. But the more you
trade, the better you start analyzing
all this information
that might seem very overwhelming at the
start. Let's move on. Number four, check
if the coin is OG. OG coins are first
coins, so coins that haven't been
launched before. If a coin is first of a
kind, its chances to pump are much
higher than a used narrative. Let's say
you want to analyze this whole tech
coin. All you got to do is just pull the
cursor over the coin name and press
search for whole tech or whatever coin
you're analyzing. And here select OG
mode. And you have a list of all the
coins with similar names. You can also
click the graduated tab to see which of
these coins graduated and as we can see,
there's only one coin with this
narrative that has graduated. So, in
this particular scenario, it is a good
thing, but I don't really like this
narrative, so let's move on. Number
five, do you understand the meme? I
don't think I need to explain this. If
you do not understand the meme coin
you're buying, then what the [__] are
you even doing? If you don't understand
a meme coin, the chances are other
traders will not understand the meme
coin. And if you're buying coins because
other people are buying them or because
they're pumping,
I think you should get a job. Number
six, is it a vamp? If yes, what type of
vamp? Let me explain. Most vamp coins
are really bad for the market because
they just copy the original coin and you
you just don't understand what to buy.
Some vamp coins even perform better than
the original coins. It's just a complete
mess. It usually happens with news coins
when a big accounts on Twitter tweet
something and people just pick it up and
start making coins about it. So, these
vamps are not good, but if a coin drops
and it reaches 100k, let's say, and then
someone finds out that the coin is
misspelled or the narrative is not fully
correct, they launch their own coin
explaining why the original coin is
wrong. And that's pretty much a really
good thing because you already see that
the narrative is good, people are buying
into the narrative. But if there's
actually a mistake in the coin, all the
attention will shift to the new one. But
the most difficult part of the strategy
is to understand, did the person
actually find a mistake in the narrative
or are they just bullshitting you? Let's
move on. And number seven, check for
fresh wallets in top holders if you're
unsure about a bundle. So, if a bundle
is happening and the coin is still being
bundled, then first of all, the bundle
number here is going to keep growing.
And another way to see it if there are
tens of buys with wallets with this logo
here, with this green leaf logo, which
means that the wallet is brand new, it's
a fresh wallet. And if you see a lot of
them side by side, especially with a
similar buy amount, then it's most
probably a bundle. All right, so this is
the full checklist. You can take a
screenshot of it. I really hope this
video helped you understand meme coin
trading a bit better. See you in the
next one.